Symianakis Sifis

Mafsolou 67, Heraklion, Crete, p.c.: 71 601 sifis.symianakis@gmail.com

Birth: September 1986. Heraklion City, Crete

Telephone: +30 6946 006 437



Resume

I am a backend software engineer working with state-of-the-art technologies and love to participate in high level designs, software implementations and best practice methodologies. I have studied Computer Science Department at University of Crete and completed master studies on ubiquitous computing at Hellenic Open University. My master thesis is based on ubiquitous systems, researching on simplifying editing and summarization video process using context. For a detailed portfolio including my published projects and applications please contact me via email.

Education

2013 - 2016 Master on Ubiquitous and Mobile Computing MSc

Hellenic Open University

Mobile Computing, Mobility, Spherical computing, Smart Environments, Ontologies, HCI of ubiquitous systems, Internet of Things, Mobile Wireless Networks.

2004 - 2009 Bachelor on Computer Science Department

University of Crete, Heraklion

Software Development, Object Oriented Programming, Design and development of information systems (UML), Advanced Programming, Network Concepts, Computer Science, Data structures, Hardware Design, Computer Organization, Compilers.

Experience

09/2018 - Today

Pancreta Bank

- Senior Software Engineer (9/2018 Present)
 - Design and develop bank's middleware layer in a micro services architecture for system-to-system integrations.
 - Software Architecture: Structure micro services based on Netflix Spring Cloud and design system-to-system integrations.
 - (Eureka service discovery, Config-Server, Zuul-Proxy, Oauth2 server)
 - Back-End Development: Develop loosely coupled micro services with concrete business capabilities. (REST APIs)
 - o Integrations: Government, E-banking vendor, Core-banking vendor, PSD2
 - o Soap Web Services: as a middleware for AADE communication
 - Unit & integration tests for delivered software
 <u>Tech Stack</u>: Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Java 8, Junit, Postgres, Oracle

- Drive software solution regarding PSD2 Open Banking Regulation
 - API Management: Develop and manage API products with IBM API Connect tool.
 - Software Integrations: Customer journey components (Strong Customer Authentication, Consent Management, Core/Web Banking, Middleware)
 - o Software Development: PSD2 APIs (Accounts, Payments, Funds Confirmation)
 - Developer's Portal: Customer support through registration, subscription and documentation

07/2014 -8/2018

Cyberlogic (e-Tourism Solutions).

- **Lead Software Developer** (8/2016-8/2018)
 - Lead development team: backend and frontend integrations
 - Follow agile methodology: scrum, 2-week sprints
- ➤ Full Stack Software Engineer (8/2015-7/2016)
 - Back-End Development: REST APIs developed with .NET, use of MSSQL relational and MongoDB document-based database
 - Follow Domain Drive Design
 - Unit Testing

Tech Stack: C#, MSSQL, MongoDB

- **Frontend Engineer** (7/2014-7-2015)
 - Front-End Development: Web applications with Angular framework
 <u>Tech Stack</u>: AngularJS, Angular(2-4), Typescript, Bootstrap, HTML5, Jasmine Testing
 - Mobile Development: Native android applications
 Tech Stack: Android framework, Android Studio, Java 7

12/2012 - **05/2013**

Front-End Developer @ Municipality of Gortys

Front-end development: Operational Site of Municipality
 <u>Tech Stack</u>: HTML, CSS, jQuery

05/2011 -05/2012

Information Technology Support @ Ministry of Health (Heraklion).

IT Support of information systems, issuing with financial and administration information systems.

10/2008 -10/2009 **Technology Sales Representative** @ OTE (Telecommunications)

Making sales of telecommunication and internet based services and equipment including after sales support.

Courses

2019 (3 days)	Voxxed Days Athens 2019: International series events focusing on software engineer technologies and tech trends.
2016 (3 days)	Droidcon Thessaloniki Conference in android framework and mobile development. Talking about new technologies and networking. #Droidcon
2016 (3 days)	Agile Unconference #AgileCrete Coach+Dev Camp 2016.

2015 (3 days) Agile Unconference #AgileCrete Coach+Dev Camp 2015. Agile Software Development.

Collaboration. Tools. Estimating. Continuous improvements. Flexibility on customers

changing minds. Agile Principles.

2011 (1 week) Designing Web Application with Open Source Tools. #Training Institute of the National

Center School of Public Administration and Local Government (EKDDA).

2011 (1 week) E-Government and Citizens. Training. #Institute of the National Center School of Public

Administration and Local Government (EKDDA).

Additional Info

Military Duties Fulfilled

Interests Software Engineering, S/E Courses, Developer Community, Books, Gaming, Sports

LinkedIn Web Page https://www.linkedin.com/in/sifis-symianakis/